<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="ticketnumber-generator">
    <title>Ticket Number Generator Modules</title>
    <para>
        Ticket number generators are used to create distinct identifiers aka ticket number for
        new tickets.
        Any method of creating a string of numbers is possible, you should use common sense about
        the length of the resulting string (guideline: 5-10).
    </para>
    <para>
        When creating a ticket number, make sure the result is prefixed by the SysConfig variable
        <literal>SystemID</literal> in order to enable the detection of ticket numbers on inbound email responses.
        A ticket number generator module needs the two functions <code>TicketCreateNumber()</code> and
        <code>GetTNByString()</code>.
    </para>
    <para>
        The method <code>TicketCreateNumber()</code> is called without parameters and returns the new ticket
        number.
    </para>
    <para>
        The method <code>GetTNByString()</code> is called with the param String which contains the string to be
        parsed for a ticket number and returns the ticket number if found.
    </para>
    <section id="ticketnumber-generator-code">
        <title>Code example</title>
        <para>
            See <filename>Kernel/System/Ticket/Number/UserRandom.pm</filename> in the package <literal>TemplateModule</literal>.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="ticketnumber-generator-configuration">
        <title>Configuration example</title>
        <para>
            See <filename>Kernel/Config/Files/TicketNumberGenerator.xml</filename> in the package <literal>TemplateModule</literal>.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="ticketnumber-generator-usecases">
        <title>Use Cases</title>
        <section id="ticketnumber-generator-usecase-10">
            <title>Ticket numbers should follow a specific scheme.</title>
            <para>
                You will need to create a new ticket number generator if the default modules don't
                provide the ticket number scheme you'd like to use.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section id="ticketnumber-generator-caveats">
        <title>Caveats and Warnings</title>
        <para>
            You should stick to the code of <code>GetTNByString()</code> as used in existing ticket number
            generators to prevent problems with ticket number parsing.
            Also the routine to detect a loop in <code>TicketCreateNumber()</code> should be kept intact to
            prevent duplicate ticket numbers.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="ticketnumber-generator-releases">
        <title>Release Availability</title>
        <para>
            Ticket number generators have been available in OTRS since OTRS 1.1.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
