<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section>
    <title>Log Mechanism</title>
    <section>
        <title>System Log</title>
        <para>
            OTRS comes with a system log backend that can be used for application logging and debugging.
        </para>
        <para>
            The log object can be accessed and used via the <literal>ObjectManager</literal> like this:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
$Kernel::OM->Get('Kernel::System::Log')->Log(
    Priority => 'error',
    Message  => 'Need something!',
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            Depending on the configured log level via <literal>MinimumLogLevel</literal> option in SysConfig, logged
            message will either be saved or not, based on their <emphasis>Priority</emphasis> flag.
        </para>
        <para>
            If <literal>error</literal> is set, just errors are logged. With <literal>debug</literal>, you get all
            logging messages. The order of log levels is:
        </para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><literal>debug</literal></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><literal>info</literal></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><literal>notice</literal></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><literal>error</literal></para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>
            The output of the system log can be directed to either a syslog daemon or log file, depending on the
            configured <literal>LogModule</literal> option in SysConfig.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Communication Log</title>
        <para>
            In addition to System Log, OTRS provides specialized logging backend for any communication related logging.
            Since OTRS 6, system comes with dedicated tables and frontends to track and display communication logs for
            easier debugging and operational overview.
        </para>
        <para>
            To take advantage of the new system, first create a non-singleton instance of communication log object:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
my $CommunicationLogObject = $Kernel::OM->Create(
    'Kernel::System::CommunicationLog',
    ObjectParams => {
        Transport   => 'Email',     # Transport log module
        Direction   => 'Incoming',  # Incoming|Outgoing
        Start       => 1,           # Put communication log in 'Processing' state immediately
        AccountType => 'POP3',      # Mail account type
        AccountID   => 1,           # Mail account ID
    },
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            When you have a communication log object instance, you can create an object log for logging individual
            messages. There are two object logs currently implemented: <literal>Connection</literal> and
            <literal>Message</literal>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <literal>Connection</literal> object log should be used for logging any connection related messages (for
            example: authenticating on server or retrieving incoming messages).
        </para>
        <para>
            Simply, create the object log and you can start using it immediately:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
my $ConnectionID = $CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLogStart(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
);

$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLog(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
    ObjectID   => $ConnectionID,
    Priority   => 'Debug',                              # Trace, Debug, Info, Notice, Warning or Error
    Key        => 'Kernel::System::MailAccount::POP3',
    Value      => "Open connection to 'host.example.com' (user-1).",
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            If you encounter an unrecoverable error, you can choose to close the object log and mark it as failed:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLog(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
    ObjectID   => $ConnectionID,
    Priority   => 'Error',
    Key        => 'Kernel::System::MailAccount::POP3',
    Value      => 'Something went wrong!',
);

$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLogStop(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
    ObjectID   => $ConnectionID,
    Status     => 'Failed',
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            In turn, you can mark the communication log as failure as well:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
$CommunicationLogObject->CommunicationStop(
    Status => 'Failed',
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            Otherwise, close the object and communication log as success:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLog(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
    ObjectID   => $ConnectionID,
    Priority   => 'Debug',
    Key        => 'Kernel::System::MailAccount::POP3',
    Value      => "Connection to 'host.example.com' closed.",
);

$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLogStop(
    ObjectType => 'Connection',
    ObjectID   => $ConnectionID,
    Status     => 'Successful',
);

$CommunicationLogObject->CommunicationStop(
    Status => 'Successful',
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            <literal>Message</literal> object log should be used for any log entries regarding specific messages and
            their processing. It is used in a similar way, just make sure to start it before using it:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
my $MessageID = $CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLogStart(
    ObjectType => 'Message',
);

$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLog(
    ObjectType => 'Message',
    ObjectID   => $MessageID,
    Priority   => 'Error',
    Key        => 'Kernel::System::MailAccount::POP3',
    Value      => "Could not process message. Raw mail saved (report it on http://bugs.otrs.org/)!",
);

$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLogStop(
    ObjectType => 'Message',
    ObjectID   => $MessageID,
    Status     => 'Failed',
);

$CommunicationLogObject->CommunicationStop(
    Status => 'Failed',
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            You also have the possibility to link the log object and later lookup the communications for a certain
            object type and ID:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
$CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLookupSet(
    ObjectID         => $MessageID,
    TargetObjectType => 'Article',
    TargetObjectID   => 2,
);

my $LookupInfo = $CommunicationLogObject->ObjectLookupGet(
    TargetObjectType => 'Article',
    TargetObjectID   => 2,
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            You should make sure to always stop communication and flag it as failed, if any log object failed as well.
            This will allow administrators to see failed communications in the overview, and take any action if needed.
        </para>
        <para>
            It's important to preserve the communication log for duration of a single process. If your work is spanning
            over multiple objects and any of them can benefit from logging, make sure to pass the existing communication
            log around so all methods can use the same one. With this approach, you will make sure any log entries
            spawned for the same process are contained in a single communication.
        </para>
        <para>
            If passing the communication log instance is not an option (async tasks!), you can also choose to recreate
            the communication log object in the same state as in previous step. Just pass the communication ID to the
            new code, and get the object via this parameter:
        </para>
        <para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[
my $CommunicationLogObject = $Kernel::OM->Create(
    'Kernel::System::CommunicationLog',
    ObjectParams => {
        CommunicationID => 123,
    },
);
            ]]></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>
            You can then continue to use this instance as previously stated, create any object logs if needed, adding
            entries and setting status in the end.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
