<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="development-environment">
    <title>Development Environment</title>
    <para>
        To facilitate the writing of OTRS expansion modules, the creation of a development environment is necessary.
        The source code of OTRS and additional public modules can be found on <ulink url="http://otrs.github.io">github</ulink>.
    </para>

    <section id="environment-cvs-checkout">
        <title>Framework checkout</title>
        <para>
            First of all a directory must be created in which the modules can be stored.
            Then switch to the new directory using the command line and check them out by using the following command:
        </para>
        <para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
# for git master
shell> git clone git@github.com:OTRS/otrs.git -b master
# for a specific branch like OTRS 3.3
shell> git clone git@github.com:OTRS/otrs.git -b rel-3_3
]]></screen>
            Check out the "module-tools" module (from github) too, for your development environment. It contains a number of useful tools:
        <screen><![CDATA[
shell> git clone git@github.com:OTRS/module-tools.git
]]></screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Please configure the OTRS system according to the
            <ulink url="http://otrs.github.io/doc/manual/admin/stable/en/html/installation.html">installation instructions</ulink>
            in the admin manual.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="environment-link-modules">
        <title>Linking Expansion Modules</title>
        <para>
            A clear separation between OTRS and the modules is necessary for proper developing.
            Particularly when using a git clone, a clear separation is crucial.
            In order to facilitate the OTRS access the files, links must be created.
            This is done by a script in the directory module tools repository.
            Example: Linking the Calendar Module:
        <screen><![CDATA[
shell> ~/src/module-tools/link.pl ~/src/Calendar/ ~/src/otrs/
]]></screen>
            Whenever new files are added, they must be linked as described above.
        </para>
        <para>
            To remove links from OTRS enter the following command:
        <screen><![CDATA[
shell> ~/src/module-tools/remove_links.pl ~/src/otrs/
]]></screen>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="environment-after-link">
        <title>Necessary Actions after Linking</title>
        <para>
            As soon as the linking is completed, the SysConfig must be rebuilt to register the module in OTRS.
            Additional SQL or Perl code from the module must also be executed:
            Example:
        <screen><![CDATA[
shell> ~/src/otrs/bin/otrs.RebuildConfig.pl
shell> ~/src/module-tools/DatabaseInstall.pl -m Calendar.sopm -a install
shell> ~/src/module-tools/CodeInstall.pl -m Calendar.sopm -a install
]]></screen>
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
